<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marium Tapal</title>
    <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marium Tapal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Guided Activity About Binary Classification in Unimodal and Multimodal Memes</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-a-guided-activity-about-binary-classification-in-unimodal-and-multimodal-memes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-a-guided-activity-about-binary-classification-in-unimodal-and-multimodal-memes/</guid>
      <description>This project attempts to teach binary classification in unimodal and multimodal memes to my classmates in the Spring 2021 Smith College Modeling for Machine Learning course in under 15 minutes.
It is based upon the The Hateful Memes Challenge: Detecting Hate Speech in Multimodal Memes paper by researchers at Facebook AI.
Here is the GitHub repo for this project. You can view the activity here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Marium Tapal!     I am a recent graduate of Smith College (a historically women&amp;rsquo;s college in Massachusetts, USA) where I studied Statistical and Data Sciences &amp;amp; Mathematics. I am passionate about data science, business analysis, research, and solving complicated mathematical equations. I am looking for full-time opportunities beginning immediately!
My primary programming language is R but I am comfortable in python, SQL, Tableau, LaTeX, and HTML/CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aligned Hierarchies</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-aligned-hierarchies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-aligned-hierarchies/</guid>
      <description>repytah is an open-source Music Information Retrieval Python package for building Aligned Hierarchies. I worked with a geographically distributed team of 6 people between May - August 2021. During my time, I
 spearheaded the software production of the package for future distribution on PyPI and Anaconda updated 8 functions and wrote &amp;gt;10000 lines of code built supporting website wrote draft paper for submission to the Journal of Open Source Software  Links:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Simple Normal Regression in R</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-automated-simple-normal-regression-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-automated-simple-normal-regression-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This project attempts to automate and greatly simplify the process of conducting a Bayesian Simple Normal Regression in R, allowing users to generate an entire report containing a fully customized analysis – including information such as model quality, proposed regression lines, posterior predictions, and more – using only a single line of code.
This project uses a parameterized R Markdown report and a simple function to perform the magic!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fec16 R Package</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-fec16-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-fec16-r-package/</guid>
      <description>  fec16 is an R data package that contains relational data for the United States 2015-2016 election cycle in the form of pre-loaded datasets and functions.
I presented an e-poster about the fec16 package at the Women in Statistical and Data Sciences 2020 conference and at the Electronic Undergraduate Statistics Research Conference.
Links:
 GitHub CRAN
 WSDS poster eUSR slides (not hosted)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fivethirtyeight R Package</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-fivethirtyeight-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-fivethirtyeight-r-package/</guid>
      <description>  fivethirtyeight is a R data package that provides access to the code and data sets published by FiveThirtyEight. I am a contributor to this package, where I used drat to author an add-on fivethirtyeightdata package to host the large datasets that were too big for CRAN. I talk more about my work in this blog post here.
Links:
 fivethirtyeight repo + website fivethirtyeightdata organization  drat repo fivethirtyeightdata repo + website   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marium Bakes - A Baking (and cooking) Website</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-marium-bakes-a-baking-and-cooking-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-marium-bakes-a-baking-and-cooking-website/</guid>
      <description>I have created (currently a WIP) a baking website using rmarkdown, HTML, and CSS, that houses my favourite tried-and-tested recipes. It is hosted via GitHub Pages at: https://mariumtapal.github.io/marium-bakes/
GitHub Repo: https://github.com/mariumtapal/marium-bakes/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ModernDive book for introductory statistics &#43; R package &#43; labs website</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-moderndive-book-for-introductory-statistics-r-package-labs-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-moderndive-book-for-introductory-statistics-r-package-labs-website/</guid>
      <description>The ModernDive textbook is a textbook for introductory statistics and data science which is available in print and as an open-source online version. Along with the textbook, there is the moderndive R package which includes data and functions to support the textbook, and a labs website that houses sample problem sets and projects as well as tips and tricks.
My contributions include cleaning up the non-user facing internal R code and text for better reproducibility, simplifying and organizing the labs website for a better user interface, and solving some issues that came up with the moderndive R package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>You can download a copy of my resume here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny App exploring NYC Civilian Complaints about the NYPD</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-shiny-app-exploring-nyc-civilian-complaints-about-the-nypd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/projects/1-shiny-app-exploring-nyc-civilian-complaints-about-the-nypd/</guid>
      <description>This Shiny app provides an interactive tool to visualize the impact of body cameras on civilian complaints against the NYPD before and after the 2017 NYC policy that requires the NYPD to release all body cam footage of incidents involving force which ended in injury or death has changed.
This project was a group project with Eleni Partakki and Elisabeth Nesmith for the Spring 2021 Smith College Visual Analytics course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2020 Data Science Internship (Praxis Funded!)</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/blog/1-summer-2020-data-science-internship-praxis-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/blog/1-summer-2020-data-science-internship-praxis-funded/</guid>
      <description>Owing to the COVID-19 pandemic, I was asked to leave my college campus mid-way through the Spring 2020 semester, which, for me, meant leaving the United States for my home in Pakistan. Amid this once-in-a-century pandemic, even though I was now 9 hours ahead of Eastern United States time (where Smith College is located), I wanted to gain some important research experience in Data Science for which, I reached out to Professor Albert Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Intro to Git/GitHub</title>
      <link>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/blog/1-workshop-intro-to-git/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariumtapal.rbind.io/blog/1-workshop-intro-to-git/github/</guid>
      <description>Hello, welcome to the intro to Git and GitHub workshop by Smithies in SDS! This workshop will primarily use the RStudio IDE to interact with Git - which I will demonstrate.
1. What is Git? What is GitHub? In short, Git is a version control system. It is a tool to manage different versions of your code/projects (i.e. a repository). GitHub, on the other hand, is a (there are a few others) hosting service for Git repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
